<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/atom.xsl" media="all"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>/tags/english/</id>
  <title>狮子山下 - English</title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[欢迎光临油腻叔的博客小站！]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/tags/english/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/tags/english/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2022-06-29T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>狮子山下</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
  </author>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/greargu/</id>
    <title>Gre Argument Essay Step by Step</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>This is an excerpt of a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OFa8oeXXuoA"><strong>youtube</strong></a> video about how to write a GRE argument essay. The author of this guide is <a href="https://www.gregmat.com/">Greg Mat</a>.</p>
<!-- excerpt -->
<p>Index:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="#question">Question</a></li>
<li><a href="#main-conclusion-assertion-or-prodiction">Main Conclusion, Assertion or Prodiction</a></li>
<li><a href="#evidence-to-support-the-conclusion">Evidence to Support the Conclusion</a></li>
<li><a href="#analyze-unstated-assumptions">Analyze (unstated assumptions)</a></li>
<li><a href="#template-organization">Template Organization</a></li>
<li><a href="#model-essay">Model Essay</a></li>
<li><a href="#main-takeaways">Main Takeaways</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="question">Question</h2>
<p>The following appeared in an editorial in a local newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;Commuters complain that increased rush-hour traffice on Blue Highway between the suburbs adn the city center has doubled their commuting time. The favored proposal of the motorists' lobby is to widen the highway, adding an additional lane of traffice. Opponents note that last year's addition of a lane to the nearby Green Highway was followed by a worsening of traffice jams on it. Their suggested alternative proposal is adding a bicycle lane to Blue Highway. Many area residents are keen bicyclists. A bicycle lane would encourage them to use bicycles to commute, it is argued, thereby reducing rush-hour traffice.&quot;</p>
<p>Write a response in which you discuss what questions would need to be answered in order to decide whether the recommendation and the argument on which it is based are reasonable. Be sure to explain how the answers to these questions would help to evaluate the recommendation.</p>
<h2 id="main-conclusion-assertion-or-prodiction">Main Conclusion, Assertion or Prodiction</h2>
<p>Opponents have proposed to add a bicycle lane to Blue Highway rather than adopt the motorist' lobby proposal to widen the highway with an additional lane.</p>
<h2 id="evidence-to-support-the-conclusion">Evidence to Support the Conclusion</h2>
<ul>
<li>Last year, the city widened Green Highway, but it led to a worsening of traffic jams on it.</li>
<li>Many area residents are keen bicyclists. a bicycle lane would encourage them to use bicycles to commute, thereby reducing rush-hour traffice.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="analyze-unstated-assumptions">Analyze (unstated assumptions)</h2>
<ul>
<li>The author is assuming that last year's issues of traffic jam on Green Highway still exists today.</li>
<li>Green Highway and Blue Highway are roughly comparable.</li>
<li>If you enjoy bicycling as a hobby, then you are likely to use that mode of transportation to commute to work.</li>
<li>these working locations are actualy within biking distance.</li>
<li>this added bicycle lane will not result in any accidents that actually cuase MORE traffice delays than the current set up.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are more assumptions, BUT you only need 2-3 of them!</p>
<h2 id="template-organization">Template Organization</h2>
<p><strong>Introduction</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Rephrase main conclustion from argument</li>
<li>Identify author's evidence and/or premises</li>
<li>Thesis (to actually follow the specific task instructions)</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Body Paragrapsh (2-3 of them)</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>First supporting idea (making sure to follow specific task instructions)</li>
<li>Example 1</li>
<li>Example 2</li>
<li>Effect on author's conclustion if examples prove true</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Statement that arguments, as it stands out, is flawed</li>
<li>Request for more evidence</li>
<li>Statement of how evidence will help evaluate the argument more effectively</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="model-essay">Model Essay</h2>
<p>in the editorial from the local newspaper, it is stated that opponents of the motorists' lobby's plan to add another lane to Blue Highway have instead advocated that a bicycle lane be constructed in order to alleviate the highway's traffcie issues. The opponents have come to this conclustion based on issued faced by Green Highway last year as well as the keen interest in bicycling of the area's local residents. <em>However, before the recommendation can be properly evaluated, three questions must be answered.</em></p>
<p>First of all, are Green Highway and Blue Highway roughly comparable? In other words, can circumstances from on highway be used to make generalizations and predictions about the other? It is possible that Green Highway and Blue Highway are not similar at all - perhaps Green Highway runs through residential neighborhoods, whereas Blue Highway is located mostly in rural, unpopulated sections of the city. Further, there is a possibility that the quality of the highways is markedly different, with Green Highway's roads falling apart and Blue Highway's in pristine condiction. If either of these scenarios has merit, then conclusion drawn in the original argument is significantly weakened.</p>
<p>Secondly, do a majority of the area residents interested in biking live within biking distance of their places of employment? The opponents in the argument prematurely assume that many of the residents in the town will bike to work in the morning rather than drive their cares. However, this might not be the case. Perhaps the average distance from home to work is over 15 miles, and that's why many of the residents are essentially obligated to take the highway - even if they don't want to. In an ideal world, they might choose to bike to work, but if the reality is such that they cannot do so due to the logistics of their situations, then only one form of transportation (the care via the highway) is possible. If the above tis true, then the argument does not hold water.</p>
<p>In conclusion, the argument, as it stands out, is considerabley flawed due to its reliance on several unwarranted assumptions. It the author is able to answer the two questions above and offer more evidence (perhaps in the form of a systematic research study), then it will be possible to fully evaluate the viability of the proposed recommendation to add a bike lane to Blue Highway.</p>
<h2 id="main-takeaways">Main Takeaways</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>When you read the argument, you are needed to identity the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>the main conclusion, main asserttion, or main prediction.</li>
<li>the premises, the evidence, or the &quot;facts&quot; that led the author to this conclusion</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>With the correct identification of the conclusion and the evidence, you have to do something very important: reason the unstated assumptions out.</p>
<ul>
<li>this is where the bulk of your writing grade for the argument essay comes from. The graders are looking for your ability to deconstruct an argument in an analytical fashion. They are asking you to think.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Structures, templates, and &quot;one way&quot; to write this essay are not essential.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Three body paragraphs are roughly the same thing within different content.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Make sure you follow the prompt's instructions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>30 minutes limit!</p>
</li>
</ol>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/greargu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2022-06-29T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2022-06-29T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/greissue/</id>
    <title>Writing the GRE Issue Essay</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>This is an excerpt of a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mhzlaHXHaK4"><strong>youtube</strong></a> video about how to write a GRE issue essay. The author of this guide is <a href="https://www.gregmat.com/">Greg Mat</a>.</p>
<!-- excerpt -->
<p>Index:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#body-paragraphs">Body Paragraphs</a></li>
<li><a href="#conclusion">Conclusion</a></li>
<li><a href="#example-question">Example Question</a></li>
<li><a href="#model-essay">Model Essay</a></li>
</ul>
<p>First of all, let's explore the structure of an issue essay:</p>
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Hook (generalization, anecdote, interesting fact, trend, quote, etc.)
○ Introduce the topic (nothing more). Don't write your thesis or supporting ideas!</li>
<li>Shift to prompt
○ Makes your essay more cohesive; an abrupt shift to your thesis is awkward</li>
<li>Thesis (most important part of the essay, by far)
○ This baby is the boss that controls everything</li>
<li>Outline (Tell your reader how you're going to structure your essay)
○ Doesn't have to be overly detailed</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="body-paragraphs">Body Paragraphs</h2>
<ul>
<li>Topic sentences that introduces supporting ideas
○ That is imperative that this introduce the overall idea of the paragraph and that it supports your thesis.</li>
<li>Example
○ You need a good example here, preferably from history, politics, economics, etc. If not possible, think of a good hypothetical. I don't want to hear about Uncle Bob.</li>
<li>Development/Explanation
○ You need to develop this idea. You need to explain how your supporting idea connects to your thesis. You need to explain why this matters.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>strong thesis route:</p>
<ul>
<li>Introduce a counterpoint that someone from the other side might use to argue against your position</li>
<li>Shut down that counterpoint and explain how it doesn't apply and doesn't hold water</li>
<li>Rephrase thesis and wrap this baby up</li>
</ul>
<p>moderate thesis route:</p>
<ul>
<li>Explain how this issue is very complex and that there are no easy answers.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="example-question">Example Question</h2>
<p>College students shoudl be encouraged to pursue subjects that interest them rather than the courses that seem most likely be lead to jobs.</p>
<p><em>Write a response in which you discuss the extent to which you agree or disagree with the recommendation and explain your reasoning for the position you take. In developping and supporting your position, describe specific circumstances in which adopting the recommendation would or would not be advantageous and explain how these examples shape your position.</em></p>
<h2 id="model-essay">Model Essay</h2>
<p>The choice of one's college majors is not a trivial one. In fact, it is not uncommon for entering students to reminate on this decision for months, perhaps years, and then, once a decision has been made, immediately begin to second guess it.<sup id="fnref1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref">1</a></sup>The prompt recommends that students not belabor this point too long and simply choose a path that conforms most closely to their interests and skills. <sup id="fnref1:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref">2</a></sup> In my opinion, I strongly agree with this suggestion and argue that students look inward rather than outward when choosing college courses for three reasons.<sup id="fnref1:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref">3</a></sup></p>
<p>To begin, the job market is ever shifting, and one decade's &quot;hot&quot; job is another decades's dying one. Thus, to choose one's professioin based solely on the availability of work is to take a short-term perspective, one that will likely backfire. <sup id="fnref1:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref">4</a></sup> For instance, in the 1950s through the 1980s, nuclear engineering was a rapidly growing field as many of the most powerful nations on Earth were not only designing and manufacturing nuclear weapons, but hundreds of nuclear power plants as well. Consequently, nuclear engineering graduates were able to find high-paying work almost immediately upon graduation. However, because of issues related to not in my back yard and recent nuclear accidents like the well-publicized Fukushima disaster, many countries are moving away from nuclear power in favor of other green technologies. Students who chose nuclear engineering in the 1970s because of the &quot;abundant&quot; job prospects were certainly facing a different job market in the 1990s - and this market has only worsened throught the 2000s. <sup id="fnref1:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref">5</a></sup> The above example illustrated that the job market is highly contingent upon unpredictable factors and that, if one assumes it is static, he or she is likely to get burned at some point in the future. It seems absurd to think of now during the current technological boom, but will the software engineering industry still possess dizzying job prospects in the future? History tells us that it will not. <sup id="fnref1:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref">6</a></sup></p>
<p>Further, even if we assume that the job market is not dynamic, that it is as unchanging as gravity, one should still pursue his or her interests because our happiness level plays a crucial role in how effectively we work. <sup id="fnref2:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref">4</a></sup> For instance, if a student who is passionate about horst training &quot;pragmatically&quot; chooses the path of computer programming becasue of the plethora of lucrattive job oppotunities, she runs the risk of finding herself in a field she abhors and a job she finds no satisfaction in. She might go to work each day, sit at her desk, adn stare at her computer screen with the horse wallpaper, wondering what could have been and the career path she could have chosen. She might complete her programming tasks haphazardly and submit subpar work. <sup id="fnref2:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref">5</a></sup> Research has consistently demonstrated that, perhaps above all other factors, happiness has the most direct effect on work efficiency. In other words, worders who find personal satisfaction in their craft not only work faster, but produce higher qualify products and services as well. Thus, on a macro scale, governments should enourage their populations to pursue their passions because, long-term, doing so leads to a more smoothly functioning economy not bogged down by worker discontentment. <sup id="fnref2:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref">6</a></sup></p>
<p>Of course, some argue that in our increasingly globalized economy competition for jobs has skyroceketed and thus it is imperative that we pursue practical paths. <sup id="fnref1:7"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref">7</a></sup>However, isn't that precisely why we should following our interests? If we do so, we're likely to do the best job possible. We're likely to compete at the highest level. We're likely to carve out a niche for ourselves in this &quot;increasingly globalized world&quot;. People who ignore their inner voices do so at their own peril. <sup id="fnref1:8"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote-ref">8</a></sup></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Hook.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:1" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Shift to prompt.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:2" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Thesis.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:3" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>topic sentence that introduces supporting idea.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:4" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a> <a href="#fnref2:4" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>example.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:5" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a> <a href="#fnref2:5" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p>explain and develop.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:6" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a> <a href="#fnref2:6" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:7">
<p>strong route: introduce a counterpoint.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:7" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:8">
<p>shut down the counterpoint and rephrase the thesis.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:8" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/greissue/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2022-06-29T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2022-06-29T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/englishnames/</id>
    <title>英文名字的由来</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.raz-kids.com/">&quot;Reading A-Z for Kids&quot;</a> 是套非常优秀的英语阅读教材。我随着监督孩子学习，自己也涨了不少见识，这里就通过 S 级的第一本书，介绍一下英文名字的由来。</p>
<!-- excerpt -->
<p>为节省时间，文章就不翻译了，直接上英文，反正能读到这篇文章的小伙伴们，这点英文不成问题。当然，我做了点删减。</p>
<p>本文目录如下：</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#family-names">Family Names</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#history">History</a></li>
<li><a href="#names-from-a-father">Names from a Father</a></li>
<li><a href="#names-from-a-place">Names from a Place</a></li>
<li><a href="#names-from-a-job">Names from a Job</a></li>
<li><a href="#names-from-a-description">Names from a Description</a></li>
<li><a href="#categories">Categories</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#changing-names">Changing Names</a></li>
<li><a href="#first-names">First Names</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#meaningful-names">Meaningful Names</a></li>
<li><a href="#family-names-as-first-names">Family Names as First Names</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#nicknames">Nicknames</a></li>
<li><a href="#epilogue">Epilogue</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>There are twenty-four other children in Tommy's class. Twelve are boys and twelve are girls.</p>
<p>Every morning, at school, Mrs. Zimmerman, the teacher, calles out the names of the children. The children shout &quot;present&quot; after they hear their names.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Boys</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Girls</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Daniel Armstrong</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Samantha Baker</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Robert Figueroa</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Kim Chan</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Andrew Fitzgerald</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jennifer Clark</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Joshua Fox</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Emily Fisher</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jason Freeman</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Rebecca Goldschmitt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jose Garcia</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Amanda Hill</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">William Gardener</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Stephanie Jackson</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Kareem Johnson</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Kawanna Macdonald</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Matthew Longfellow</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Isabelle Redriguez</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Michael O'Brian</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Brittany Schumacher</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Thomas Tomkins</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Ashley Taylor</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Christopher Wood</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Sarah White</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">David Yamamura</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="family-names">Family Names</h2>
<p>Your last name is your family name. Your first name is your given name. It's called &quot;given name&quot; because your parents give it to you.</p>
<p>Your family name has probably been in your family for hundreds of years.</p>
<h3 id="history">History</h3>
<p>At one time many years ago, people had only one name, a given name.</p>
<p>People lived in small villages wehre everyone knew each other. Over the years, the population increased. In the towns and villages many people had the same name, and it started to get confusing.</p>
<p>In one village there may have been eight men called John. The villagers had to add words to the different Johns' names to understand which John they were talking about.</p>
<p>Some of the Johns were known by adding their father's name. For example, John, David's son, or John, Jack's son.</p>
<p>Others were known by where they lived. For example, John from the hill, or John from the lake.</p>
<p>Others were known by the job they did. For example, John the carpenter or John the gardener.</p>
<p>Still others were known by some personal feature. For example, John the short, or John with white hair.</p>
<p>Since the Middle Ages, the rulers of many countries wanted to know who everyone was in their country, so they can collect taxes without any mistakes. Laws were passed that said everyone had to have a last name.</p>
<p>In our example village, John, David's son became John <em>Davidson</em>. John, Jack's sone became John <em>Jackson</em>. John from the lake became John <em>Lake</em>, John from the hill became John <em>Hill</em>. John the carpenter become John <em>Carpenter</em>, and John the gardener became John <em>Gardener</em>. John the short became John <em>Short</em>. John with white hair became John <em>White</em>.</p>
<p>Our last names are usually based on one of the four groups:</p>
<ol>
<li>father's name</li>
<li>place where they lived</li>
<li>job or trade</li>
<li>person's appearance</li>
</ol>
<p>Let's look at all the children in Tommy's class and divide their names into the four groups.</p>
<h3 id="names-from-a-father">Names from a Father</h3>
<ul>
<li><em>Fitz</em> means &quot;son of&quot; and came from France. <em>Fitzgerald</em> meant &quot;sone of Gerald&quot;</li>
<li><em>Johnsone</em> started off as &quot;John's son&quot;, and <em>Jackson</em> as &quot;Jack's son&quot;</li>
<li><em>Mac</em> and <em>Mc</em> mean &quot;son of&quot; and occur in Scottish and Irish names. <em>Macdonald</em> meant &quot;son of Donald&quot;</li>
<li><em>O'</em> means &quot;son of&quot; and is used in Irish names. &quot;O'Brian&quot; meant &quot;son of Brian&quot;</li>
<li><em>kins</em> at the end of a name formed a nickname meaning &quot;little&quot;. <em>Tomkins</em> meant &quot;little Tom&quot;, or &quot;Tom's little one&quot;</li>
<li><em>ez</em> at the end of a name meant &quot;son of&quot; in Spanish. <em>Rodriguez</em> meant &quot;son of Roderick&quot;</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Common Names from Father's First Name</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Son of</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Last Name</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">William</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Williams<br>Williamson</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Will</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Wilkins<br>Wilson</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Watt</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Watson<br>Watkins</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">John</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jones</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Harry</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Harrison<br>Harris<br>Parry</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Robin</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Robinson<br>Robbins</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Richard</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Richards<br>Richardson<br>Prichard</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Robert</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Robertson<br>Roberts<br>Probert</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Eric</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Ericson</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Adam</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Adams<br>McAdam</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Peter</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Peterson<br>Peters</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Evan</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Evans<br>Bevan<br>Evanson</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="names-from-a-place">Names from a Place</h3>
<ul>
<li><em>Figueroa</em> means &quot;where the fig trees grow&quot; in Spanish. So Robert Figueroa's ancestors came from a place where fig trees grew in Spain.</li>
<li><em>Garcia</em> is the name of a place in Spain, so Jose's ancestors came from this town.</li>
<li><em>Yamamura</em> is Japanese. <em>Yama</em> means &quot;mountian&quot; and <em>mura</em> means &quot;village&quot;. David's ancestors came from a village in the mountains of Japan.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Common Names from Places</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Place</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Last Name</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from a moor</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Moore</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from near a hall</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hall</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from near a village green</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Green</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from near a mill</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Mills</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from near a barn</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Barnes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from near a ford (river crossing)</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Ford</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from near a lake</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Lake</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from near a brook</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Brooks</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from near a marsh</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Marsh</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from near a lane</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Lane</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">from the country of Holland</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Holland</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="names-from-a-job">Names from a Job</h3>
<p>The ancestors of the children in the class with &quot;job&quot; names were bakers, clerks, fishermen, gardeners, goldsmiths, and tailors.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Schumacher</em> menas &quot;shoemaker&quot; in German, so Brittany had an ancestor who made shoes.</li>
<li>Jason Freeman's ancestors were salves. They were captured in Africa and brought, against their will, to America to work in the fields. When slavery was abolished, they were able to choose their own names. Many picked the names of their former masters. Some, like Jason's ancestors, chose the name <em>Freeman</em>.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jobs No Longer Exist but Names Live on</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Name</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Job Description</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Cooper</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">A cooper made wooden barrels</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hooper</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">A hooper made hoops for barrels</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Archer and Bowman</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Archers and bowman were soldiers who used a bow and arrows</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Fletcher</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">A fletcher made arrows</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Carter</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">A carter made or drove carts</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Wheeler</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">A Wheeler made wheels for the carts</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Tanner</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">A tanner worked with leather</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><br>
<strong>Ohter Common Names from Jobs</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Last Name</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Job or Trade</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Smith</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">blacksmith</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Farmer</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">farmworker</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Miller</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">worked in a flour mill</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Shepherd</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">took care of sheep</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Cook</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">cooked food</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Potter</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">made pots</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="names-from-a-description">Names from a Description</h3>
<ul>
<li>The first ancestor of Daniel <em>Armstrong</em> with a last name was known as a strong man.</li>
<li>Chan is Chinese and means &quot;old&quot;, so the first person to have a last name in Kim's family was old.</li>
<li>Joshua <em>Fox</em>'s ancestor was probably cunning, like a fox.</li>
<li><em>Longfellow</em> was a tall person and <em>White</em> had white hair.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Common Names from Description</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Last Name</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Description</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Brown</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">brown skin or hair</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Young</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">yound person</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Gray</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">gray hair</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Bird</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">timid, like a bird</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Long</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">tall person</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Peacock</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">pround or showy, like a peacock</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Lamb</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">meek, like a lamb</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Whitehead</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">with white hair</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Bull</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">wild and dangerous, like a bull</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Short</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">a short person</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="categories">Categories</h3>
<p>Now we can group children's last names and put them into four categories.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Father</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Place</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Job</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Description</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Fitzgerald<br>Johnson<br>Jackson<br>Macdonald<br>O'Brian<br>Tomkins<br>Rodriguez</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Figueroa<br>Garcia<br>Hill<br>Wood<br>Yamamura</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Baker<br>Clark<br>Fisher<br>Freeman<br>Gardener<br>Goldschmitt<br>Shumacher<br>Taylor</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Armstrong<br>Chan<br>Fox<br>Longfellow<br>White</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="changing-names">Changing Names</h2>
<p>Sometimes family names were changed for different reasons. Many of the people going to America from Europe had difficult names to pronounce and spell. To make things less difficult, they changed their names.</p>
<p>Sometimes, people arrived in the country and an official would change their name for them. This was because the official couldn't understand them when he asked them their names, or he couldn't spell it properly.</p>
<ul>
<li>Someone called <em>Jan Micsza</em> would have become <em>John Mcshea</em>.</li>
<li>Someone with the last name of <em>Mlynar</em> would become <em>Miller</em>.</li>
<li><em>Hildergart Zimmerman</em>, German for &quot;carpenter&quot;, would become <em>Hilda Carpenter</em>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Sometimes actors and singer change their names so that people will remember them more easily, like <em>Babyface</em> from Kenneth Brian Edmonds, <em>Tom Cruise</em> from Thomas Cruise Mapother IV, <em>Eminem</em> from Marshall mathers III, <em>Elton John</em> from Reginald Kenneth Dwight, <em>Madonna</em> from Madonna Louise Ciccone, <em>Sting</em> from Gordon Matthew Sumner, <em>Tiger Woods</em> from Eldrick Woods.</p>
<h2 id="first-names">First Names</h2>
<p>Now let's look at given names or first names.</p>
<h3 id="meaningful-names">Meaningful Names</h3>
<p>Most first names have meanings, which are very old and now forgotten.</p>
<p><strong>Meanings of Some Common First Names</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Name</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Meaning</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Language</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Ashley</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">from the ash tree</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Old English</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Brittany</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">a woman from Britain</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Irish</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Stephanie</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">crown</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Greek</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Amanda</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">lovable</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Latin</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Michael</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Who is like God</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hebrew</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Andrew</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">courageous</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Greek</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Robert</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">bright fame</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">English</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">David</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">friend</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hebrew</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="family-names-as-first-names">Family Names as First Names</h3>
<p>In the past few years, it has become popular to use family names as first names. Some examples:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tyler, originally a family name from someone who put tiles on roofs</li>
<li>Hunter, a hunter</li>
<li>Logan, Irish, from a cove</li>
<li>Mason, a stone mason</li>
<li>Blake, Old English, white</li>
<li>Tanner, English, leather-worker</li>
<li>Morgan, Welsh, sea dweller</li>
<li>Haley, English, hay meadow</li>
<li>Brooke, lived near a brook</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="nicknames">Nicknames</h2>
<p>Very often, first names are shortened or changed. These names are called nicknames. Let's look at Tommy's class and see how many nicknames there are.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Boys</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Nicknames</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Daniel Armstrong</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Danny</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Robert Figueroa</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Bobby</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Andrew Fitzgerald</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Andy</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Joshua Fox</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Josh</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jason Freeman</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Flash<sup id="fnref1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref">1</a></sup></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jose Garcia</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">N/A</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">William Gardener</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Billy</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Kareem Johnson</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">KJ</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Matthew Longfellow</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Matt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Michael O'Brian</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Mike</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Thomas Tomkins</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Tommy</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Christopher Wood</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Chris</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">David Yamamura</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Dave</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left;">Girls</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Nicknames</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Samantha Baker</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Sam</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Kim Chan</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">N/A</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jennifer Clark</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jenny</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Emily Fisher</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Em</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Rebecca Goldschmitt</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Becky</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Amanda Hill</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Mandy</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Stephanie Jackson</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Stephie</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Kawanna Macdonald</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Mac</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Isabelle Redriguez</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Bella</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Brittany Schumacher</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Britt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Ashley Taylor</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Spud<sup id="fnref1:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref">2</a></sup></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left;">Sarah White</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">N/A</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="epilogue">Epilogue</h2>
<p>假使有人问你，玛格丽特·撒切尔夫人（ <em>Ms. Margaret Thatcher</em>）的夫婿祖上是从事什么职业，你能猜到么？</p>
<p>如果你知道英文名的由来，那大概就能猜个八九不离十，因为 thatch 是茅草屋顶的意思，而 thatcher 是指修屋顶的工匠，原来他们老家是修屋顶的手艺人！</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Jason is called <em>Flash</em>, but that's not because of his name, but because he runs fast.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:1" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Ashley is called <em>Spud</em> because she eats a lot of potatoes.&#160;<a href="#fnref1:2" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/englishnames/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2022-06-21T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2022-06-21T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
  </entry>
</feed>
